Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
How are you, Erika?
你好吗，Erika？
Marco, I'm doing really well.
Marco，我很好。
How about you?
你呢？
I'm doing great.
我也很好。
I'm really excited because today we're talking about travel.
我很兴奋，因为今天我们要谈论旅行。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to give you some real English to talk about travel.
我们将教你们一些谈论旅行的地道英语。
Exactly.
正是。
English that you would use in everyday life, that you hear in movies and TV shows.
那些你在日常生活中会用到、在电影和电视节目中听到的英语。
English people actually use.
人们实际使用的英语。
Exactly.
没错。
So why don't you tell us a little bit about this lesson for today?
那么，你给我们介绍一下今天的课程吧？
Okay, so today we are going to listen as a husband and wife get ready to go on a trip.
好的，今天我们将听到一对夫妻准备去旅行的对话。
All right.
好的。
That sounds a little bit complicated.
听起来有点复杂。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Well, let's look at our two preview words.
我们先来看两个预览词汇。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Okay.
好的。
So the first word that we have is road trip.
第一个词是road trip。
Road trip.
公路旅行。
Okay.
好的。
So road trips are really fun and interesting, right?
公路旅行真的很有趣，对吧？
Road trips are great.
公路旅行很棒。
You get to get in a car with your family and drive on a vacation.
你可以和家人一起开车去度假。
Yeah, those are really fun and they're really popular in North America.
是的，真的很有趣，而且在北美很流行。
Really popular.
非常流行。
I've been on a million road trips.
我经历过无数次公路旅行。
All right.
好的。
We'll talk about that a little bit later on.
我们稍后再谈这个。
But now, let's take a look at our second word and it's the car's packed.
现在，我们来看第二个词：the car's packed。
The car's packed.
车装满了。
The car is packed.
So when your car is packed, it means that...
所以当你的车装满了，意思是……
Everything you need is inside the car.
你需要的一切都在车里。
All right.
好的。
So your bags, your food, everything that you need for your trip.
所以你的行李、食物，旅行所需的一切。
Exactly.
没错。
Perfect.
完美。
Okay.
好的。
So those were our two preview words and now we are ready to listen to the dialogue for
以上就是我们的两个预览词，现在我们准备第一次听对话。
the first time.
第一次。
Okay.
好的。
This dialogue will be at normal speed.
这个对话将以正常语速进行。
It will be fast.
会很快。
But don't worry if you don't understand everything.
但如果你没完全听懂，别担心。
After 10 minutes, we promise you will understand everything in this lesson.
十分钟后，我们保证你会理解这节课的所有内容。
So are we all ready to go?
那么我们都准备好了吗？
Yep.
嗯。
I think so.
我觉得好了。
The car's packed.
车已经装好了。
We have munchies and music and the map's in the car.
我们有零食、音乐，地图也在车里。
Did you get the camera?
你拿相机了吗？
Got it.
拿了。
Did you fill up the tank?
你加满油了吗？
Yep.
嗯。
It's all set.
都准备好了。
You're sure we're not forgetting anything?
你确定我们没忘什么东西？
I'm sure.
我确定。
We've got all our bases covered.
我们方方面面都考虑到了。
Well, let's get going then.
那我们就出发吧。
I love road trips.
我喜欢公路旅行。
Do you think we can make a pit stop?
你觉得我们能中途停一下吗？
But we've only been on the road for 10 minutes.
但我们才上路十分钟。
I know.
我知道。
But I forgot to go to the bathroom before we left.
但我出发前忘了上厕所。
Well she forgot to go to the bathroom.
她忘了上厕所。
Yeah.
是啊。
I hate it when this happens.
我讨厌这种情况。
This happens to me on almost every road trip.
我几乎每次公路旅行都会遇到这种情况。
Okay.
好的。
Great.
很好。
So now it's time for our language takeaway.
现在是我们的语言要点时间。
We have three words for our language takeaway today.
今天的语言要点有三个词。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
And the first word is munchies.
第一个词是 munchies。
Munchies.
Munchies。
So munchies are...
所以 munchies 就是……
Snacks.
零食。
Food.
食物。
Chips.
薯片。
Cookies.
饼干。
Chocolate bars.
巧克力棒。
All that good stuff.
所有那些好东西。
I love munchies.
我喜欢零食。
And they're really good when you're taking a road trip.
而且当你自驾游的时候，它们特别棒。
Indeed.
确实。
Okay.
好的。
So let's take a look at our second language takeaway word for today.
那我们来看看今天第二个语言要点词。
And it is fill up the tank.
那就是 fill up the tank。
Fill up the tank.
Fill up the tank。
So this is to...
这个意思是……
Put gas in your car.
给车加油。
Put gas in the gas tank.
把汽油加进油箱。
In the gas tank.
在油箱里。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
Our last language takeaway today is...
今天最后一个语言要点是……
Pit stop.
Pit stop。
Make a pit stop.
Make a pit stop。
It's a quick stop for you to get some gas, food, go to the bathroom.
就是短暂停留，加油、吃东西、上厕所。
Yeah.
是的。
A pit stop.
Pit stop。
A quick stop.
短暂停留。
Great.
很好。
So now it's time for putting it together.
现在是时候把它们组合起来了。
Putting it together.
总结一下。
Okay.
好的。
So we have two great phrases for you today.
今天我们有两个很棒的短语要教给大家。
Let's take a look at the first one.
我们来看第一个。
We've got all our bases covered.
我们已面面俱到。
This is a really great phrase and it's really useful, right?
这个短语真的很棒，也很有用，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Let's listen to a couple of examples.
我们来听几个例子。
Example one.
例子一。
We've got all our bases covered in case the hurricane hits.
我们已经做好了万全准备，以防飓风来袭。
Example two.
例子二。
Okay.
好的。
I have my keys, wallet, and passport.
我带了钥匙、钱包和护照。
Looks like I have all my bases covered.
看来我准备齐全了。
Okay.
好的。
It's clear now, but you can use this in a lot of different situations, right?
现在清楚了，但你可以在很多不同场合使用它，对吧？
You can use this in many situations.
你可以在很多场合使用它。
If I'm at work, I could say, all right, we've got a really good marketing plan.
如果我在工作，我可以说，好的，我们有一个很好的营销计划。
We've got all our bases covered.
我们已面面俱到。
Exactly.
没错。
You have everything ready.
你一切都准备好了。
You're all prepared.
你全都准备好了。
Perfect.
完美。
All right.
好的。
Now, let's take a look at our second phrase and it's, let's get going.
现在，我们来看第二个短语，那就是，我们开始吧。
Let's get going.
我们开始吧。
All right.
好的。
So, when you say, let's get going, it just means...
所以，当你说“我们开始吧”，它的意思就是……
Let's start.
开始吧。
Let's go.
走吧。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
But the interesting thing about this phrase is you can change it a little bit and it means
但这个短语有趣的地方在于，你可以稍微改变它，意思就会
something different.
有所不同。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Let's listen to a couple of examples.
我们来听几个例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I have the chicken, so let's get cooking.
我拿到鸡肉了，那我们开始做饭吧。
Example two.
例子二。
This house is really scary.
这房子真吓人。
Let's get out of here.
我们快离开这里。
Example three.
例子三。
I have another meeting in 20 minutes, so let's get down to business.
我二十分钟后还有个会，所以我们直接谈正事吧。
So let's get down to business, Marco.
那我们直接谈正事吧，马可。
Let's get down to business.
我们直接谈正事吧。
Let's listen to the dialogue one more time, but this time...
我们再听一遍对话，但这次……
It'll be a little bit slower and you'll understand much better.
语速会慢一点，你会理解得更好。
So are we all ready to go?
我们都准备好了吗？
Yep, I think so.
是的，我想是的。
The car's packed, we have munchies and music, and the map's in the car.
车装好了，我们有零食和音乐，地图也在车里。
Did you get the camera?
你拿相机了吗？
Got it.
拿了。
Did you fill up the tank?
你加满油了吗？
Yep, it's all set.
是的，都准备好了。
You're sure we're not forgetting anything?
你确定我们没忘什么东西？
I'm sure.
我确定。
We've got all our bases covered.
我们该准备的都准备好了。
Well, let's get going then.
好吧，那我们出发吧。
I love road trips.
我喜欢公路旅行。
Um, do you think we can make a pit stop?
嗯，你觉得我们能中途停一下吗？
But we've only been on the road for 10 minutes.
但我们才上路十分钟。
I know, but I forgot to go to the bathroom before we left.
我知道，但我出发前忘了上厕所。
So that was a little more clear this time, wasn't it?
所以这次清楚多了，对吧？
Yeah, you can definitely understand better about what we've been talking about.
是的，你肯定能更好地理解我们在说什么。
Yep.
嗯。
Okay, so now it's time to look at Fluency Builder.
好了，现在是时候看看流利度构建器了。
Erika, why don't you explain what Fluency Builder is?
埃里卡，你来解释一下什么是流利度构建器吧。
In Fluency Builder, we give you some great, useful phrases to help you express your ideas
在流利度构建器中，我们提供一些很棒、有用的短语，帮助你清晰地表达想法。
clearly.
清晰。
Okay, great.
好的，太好了。
So let's look at Fluency Builder.
那我们来看看流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
All right, so we all know how to ask the question, are we ready to go?
好了，我们都知道怎么问“我们准备好了吗？”这个问题。
That's right.
没错。
Can we go now?
我们现在能走了吗？
Or you can say, are we ready to go?
或者你可以说，我们都准备好出发了吗？
Exactly.
没错。
But there's another way that we can say this, and we heard it in our dialogue.
但还有另一种说法，我们在对话中听到了。
So let's listen.
我们来听一下。
So are we all ready to go?
那么我们都准备好出发了吗？
Wow, that sounds really good.
哇，听起来真不错。
It sounds a lot more fluent.
听起来流利多了。
Fluent, exactly.
流利，没错。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, so another simple phrase that we all know how to say is, it is ready.
好的，另一个我们都会说的简单短语是，它准备好了。
It is prepared.
它准备好了。
It is ready.
Right.
对。
So these examples are fine.
这些例子没问题。
They're right.
它们是正确的。
Yeah, they're correct English, no problem.
是的，它们是正确的英语，没问题。
But there's another way to say this that we heard in the dialogue, and it sounds a lot
但我们在对话中听到了另一种说法，听起来
more fluent.
更流利。
Yep, it's all set.
是的，都准备好了。
It's all set.
都准备好了。
That sounds much better.
听起来好多了。
Yes, and we're all set to listen to this dialogue for a third time, and this time it's going
是的，我们都准备好第三次听这段对话了，这次将以
to be at its normal speed.
正常速度播放。
So are we all ready to go?
那么我们都准备好出发了吗？
Yep, I think so.
是的，我想是的。
The car's packed.
车装好了。
We have munchies and music and the map's in the car.
我们有零食和音乐，地图也在车里。
Did you get the camera?
你拿相机了吗？
Got it.
拿了。
Did you fill up the tank?
你加满油了吗？
Yep, it's all set.
是的，都准备好了。
You're sure we're not forgetting anything?
你确定我们没忘什么东西？
I'm sure.
我确定。
We've got all our bases covered.
我们方方面面都考虑到了。
Well, let's get going then.
好吧，那我们出发吧。
I love road trips.
我喜欢公路旅行。
Do you think we can make a pit stop?
你觉得我们能中途停一下吗？
But we've only been on the road for 10 minutes.
但我们才上路10分钟。
I know, but I forgot to go to the bathroom before we left.
我知道，但我出发前忘了上厕所。
So, Erika, you said you've been on a million road trips.
那么，Erika，你说你经历过无数次公路旅行。
What was that all about?
那是怎么回事？
Where have you been?
你去过哪些地方？
Okay, well, maybe not a million road trips, but many road trips.
好吧，也许不是无数次，但确实很多次。
Every summer I used to go on a road trip with my family, and we would drive many, many hours,
每年夏天我都会和家人一起公路旅行，我们会开很多很多小时的车，
probably eight hours in one day, up to northern Canada.
可能一天八小时，一路开到加拿大北部。
Oh, wow, nice.
哦，哇，真不错。
Yeah, and then we would go camping, and we would sleep outside, and we would have a campfire
是啊，然后我们会去露营，睡在外面，晚上还会生篝火。
at night.
晚上。
It was great.
太棒了。
Ah, family road trip.
啊，家庭公路旅行。
Yeah, but maybe eight hours in a car is a little too long.
是啊，但也许在车里待八个小时有点太长了。
Well, yeah.
嗯，确实。
Well, I've been on a different kind of road trip with some buddies of mine, some friends.
嗯，我和几个哥们儿有过另一种公路旅行。
We would drive to Las Vegas.
我们会开车去拉斯维加斯。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
So that's really fun.
那真的很有趣。
A bunch of crazy guys in a car going to Las Vegas, and then just having fun and talking
一群疯狂的家伙坐在车里前往拉斯维加斯，尽情玩乐，无所不谈。
about everything.
谈论一切。
So that's a much different experience than a family road trip.
所以这和家庭公路旅行是完全不同的体验。
Maybe that sounds a little bit more fun.
也许那听起来更有趣一些。
Yeah, eight hours in a car is not really that boring with all your friends.
是啊，和所有朋友在一起，在车里待八个小时其实并不无聊。
All right, folks, we're out of time for today, but be sure to visit our website at EnglishPod.com
好了，朋友们，今天的时间到了，但一定要访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，
and leave all your questions and comments.
留下你们的所有问题和评论。
Okay, well, thanks for listening, and until next time, goodbye.
好的，感谢收听，下次再见，拜拜。
Bye.
再见。